<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Courses on PEMCLAB</title>
    <link>https://yhtzou.github.io/categories/courses/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Courses on PEMCLAB</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yhtzou.github.io/categories/courses/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>數位交流驅動控制器之設計與實現</title>
      <link>https://yhtzou.github.io/posts/2021032401/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yhtzou.github.io/posts/2021032401/</guid>
      <description>Topics #   Introduction Converter Topology for AC Drives Control Interface for Digital Servo Motor Control Digital AC Servo Motor Controller Requirements Evolution of DSP Motor Controllers Digital Motor Control ICs Practical Issues in Digital Motion Control 808-PowerLab Research on Digital Motor Control  Introduction #   Motor Drives for Manufacturing Automation Composition of a Motion Control System State of the Art: AC Servos Block Diagram of a Typical Digital Motor Controller DSP Solution for Motor Control Characteristics of Power Electronic Systems Journals and Conferences  Composition of a Motion Control System #   The servo motor is connected to a mechanical load The tacho-generator is usually not used in modern digital servo drive The servo drive unit may be multiple-axis and consists of a motion controller The control unit provides man-machine interface  Modern Digital AC Servo Drive #  Typical Time and Frequency Responses #   An example of motor current waveforms and Bode diagram of the whole system: (a) speed response to step command and primary-phase current waveform; (b) Bode diagrams of the speed-control system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>電動機控制</title>
      <link>https://yhtzou.github.io/posts/2021031101/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yhtzou.github.io/posts/2021031101/</guid>
      <description>課程簡介 #  課程名稱： 電動機控制 5062 Smart Power Processing for Energy Saving
指導教授： 鄒應嶼教授 Prof. Ying-Yu Tzou
國立陽明交通大學 電機控制工程研究所
Lab 808 電力電子系統與晶片實驗室
Power Electronic Systems &amp;amp; Chips, NYCU, TAIWAN
課程內容 #  本課程介紹電動機控制的基本原理、功率放大器、與控制方法，以永磁直流電機之驅動控制為基礎，介紹感應電機、永磁同步電機、無刷直流電機的工作原理、數學模型、驅動控制、與實現技術。課程內容強調基本原理、控制方法與實務應用的結合，使用電腦模擬軟體 Matlab / Simulink 進行電機驅動控制系統的特性分析與控制模擬。
課程內容特別著重利用 Matlab-Simulink 進行電機驅動控制系統的分析與模擬，利用 PSIM、PLECS 模擬電機驅動器，在輔以 Matlab-Simulik 進行系統整合設計的設計優化 (Design Optimization)。
課程教材 #  教課書、講義與指定參考書籍
 Fundamentals of Electrical Drive, 2E, Andre Veltman, Duco W.J. Pulle, R.W. de Doncker, Springer, 2016. Advanced Electrical Drives - Analysis, Modeling, Control, Rik De Doncker, Duco W.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
